so joh I've heard you talk a lot about
Discerning things not being in my
control and I think I do see this to
some extent what still confuses me a bit
though is how exactly this translates to
making one not identify with those
things or to release from suffering to
be released from
suffering for
instance I know I can't control my body
but I still find myself identifying with
I can't control my feelings but I still
feel like I'm the one feeling them I
didn't choose my character traits but
still they make me who I am is there a
step I am missing or am I not seeing the
lack of control on the right level both
so you're not seeing the lack of control
on the right level because if you do uh
un identification with those things will
be
automatic in other words it would be the
result of your seeing you wouldn't have
to then well I need to see things that
that are not in my control and now I
need to also unidentify myself with them
no seeing that it's not in your control
means you you cannot be identified with
it so uh basically the problem is that
your idea of non-control is
abstract which is why practically you
are still very much identified with
things because practically you still
seek pleasure in your body you still
find safety in your possessions and
fundamentally you do not see the Peril
and the danger of those things so if you
want to contemplate the non-control
rightly like of course you can get
information and think about the aspects
of non-control but that's pretty much
abstract you want to contemplate
non-control contemplate the danger in
things that you takeen to be yours that
you control the Peril the danger of
losing them the danger of them changing
so in regard to your own body
contemplate the the terminal illness
death and these things and even if you
don't think in terms of non-control you
will be very much EXP experiencing the
non-control on that emotional
level